Sergey Kuznetsov Senior UI/UX Designer / Art Director

Moscow, Russia · +7 977 494 6537 · psjavie@gmail.com · tg:@javiejacie · linkedin.com/in/javiejacie

SUMMARY

Senior UI/UX Designer and Art Director, with 13 years of experience in web and mobile interfaces, product design and graphic design. I work with design agencies, marketing teams of small and medium-sized businesses, product companies, and startups across IT, finance, transport, education, and business sectors. I create user-friendly, business-oriented client solutions and visual design systems, build products and services from scratch, and improve existing products in close collaboration with development teams. My process includes audience analysis, metrics, and user journey mapping. I combine scenario-based and strategic thinking, and maintain a fast working pace. I approach problems critically and ask unconventional, insightful questions. 8 years of leadership experience.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

UI/UX Designer • Art director Darwin Apps, Reston, USA

2021 — Now

- Created a design department inside of the existing digital agency, assembled a multidisciplinary design team of 6 creatives, created and led design development processes, building products and web resources.
- Participated in 10+ tenders, and 20+ projects, crafting tailored design concepts, interactive prototypes, and video presentations for web and mobile applications.
- Led the comprehensive redesign of the AFR100 (African Forest Landscape Restoration Initiative) portal, a platform supporting 34 African countries committed to restoring over 129 million hectares of degraded land, increasing it in user engagement metrics, including a 40% rise in average session duration and a 25% boost in page views per session, indicating improved user interaction and content relevance.
- Boosted social media presence by creating a system of publications, growing Dribbble followers to 3,200 and Behance to 580 organically; featured in Behance's UI project curation.
- Redesigned multiple lead-generation portals for Bennie, an employee benefits platform with \$50M in funding, enhancing user engagement and conversion rates (Bennie.com, HRAdvisory, Sayge).

Product Designer • Art director SoftPro, Moscow, Russia

2018 - 2022

- Participation in IT initiatives of a sports conglomerate, including business packaging for subsidiary brands. Responsible for building conversion funnels, landing pages, visual identity, graphics, and custom illustrations.
- Designed a website and an educational online platform for the biggest chess school in russia, that had graduated over 40,000 people, raised over 100 champions, has over 90 coaches on staff in 40+ branches.
- Led feature design and delivery for the core product a sports media platform. Collaborated with engineering teams, developed and maintained a scalable design system, and created interactive prototypes for key user flows.

UI/UX Designer • Product Designer • Art director Technesis, Moscow, Russia

2018 - 2020

- Led and contributed to the design of 20+ digital services for different devices, optimizing UI/UX across existing transport and engineering IT products and ensuring consistent user experience.
- Oversaw full-cycle design development of a mobile ticketing app for intercity transport with an admin system for operators. The solution improved boarding speed by 30% and boosted ticket sales by 20% in early adoption regions and it is used in transporting companies of 15+ regions of the Russian Federation.
- Designed the Kaliningrad Go App a government-backed, cross-platform travel platform. Achieved 70K+ installs in 6 months, ranked #1 in the local App Store category, integrated 250+ locations, and reached 40% monthly retention.

UI/UX Designer • Design Lead Docomo Digital, Moscow, Russia

2017 — 2018

• Worked within an autonomous design unit, delivering full-cycle visual communication for the Russian branch of a global IT company.

- Led design campaigns integrating 20+ services with mobile carrier billing systems, improving user conversion by an estimated 18%.
- Led end-to-end design of a digital reading cross-platform web service for magazines of "Burda" publishing house, featuring a library of publications of over 10 years of publishing 30+ magazines across lifestyle, multimedia and other categories.

Product Designer • UI/UX Designer

2017 - 2018

Anywayanyday, Moscow, Russia.

- Collaborated with a team of 2 designers and developers to create a cross-platform booking service with 40% of direct visits, contributing to feature development and user experience improvements.
- Designed logistics service Smart Seeds, a management b2b product that is used by 10K+ transporting companies in 25 regions of the Russian Federation. I designed a visual guideline that remains relevant for 8 years.

UI/UX Designer • Art director Zephyrlab, Moscow, Russia

2014 - 2017

- In 5 days Launched "Our Forest" government and public initiative landing page and customer funnel and gained a web design award Tagline 2015.
- Designed the "Dobrodel" platform for the Moscow Region Government, which received the Runet Prize in 2015 and addressed over 2.3 million citizen-reported issues.
- Created design concepts and led the design team for the "MTS Money" wallet mobile app, collaborating closely with the development team. (5 million downloads B Google Play and ~1.5 Monthly Active Users)

Web Designer 2012 — 2014

Foremost Design, Moscow, Russia

- In a team of 4 designers and 3 developers we designed 5+ web portals including ones in wedding & restaurant themes, built reusable design systems and visual style for them.
- Served 20+ clients with brand identity, UX/UI for web/apps, and marketing assets.
- Created IT ecosystem for innovative car washing company Park-n-Go: management application, web resources, brand style, logo and marketing assets.

PROJECT WORK

UI/UX Designer • Product designer

2021

INANOMO, Remote

- Led full-cycle design of web & mobile trading platform.
- Delivered 20+ UI screens, supported development process for 2 months...

UI/UX Designer • Product designer

2024

Finmars, Remote

- Full cycle of logo and branding design, redesigned an existing visual system according to the new positioning of the product and existing audience communication.
- Provided product dev team with human resources.

EDUCATION

Moscow University of Economics, Statistics and Informatics (MESI), Faculty of Information Technology, major in Mathematical Support and Administration of Information Systems, 2009-2014

LANGUAGES

Russian: Native / English: B2

SKILLS

UX/UI Design, Product design, Graphic Design, Motion Design, Interactive Prototyping, Design Systems, Typography, Mobile & Desktop Application Design, Design Management, Design Strategy, User Research, Visual Design, Figma, Miro, Adobe Creative Suite, Usability Testing, Agile, Scrum, Chat GPT, Midjourney.